Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/isak-bosman (LinkedIn) geekonedge.com (Blog)

Top Skills

Software Development
Machine Learning
TensorFlow

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Isak Bosman

Helping you succeed with AI and Machine Learning | Machine Learning Developer + Data Scientist + Speaker + Teacher Orange County, California Area

Summary

I help you succeed with Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.

It's clear that AI is going to change everything. I have nearly 15 years of experience in helping organizations find hidden value in their data and identify high ROI machine learning opportunities. I am passionate about teaching developers the latest techniques and tools to use in achieving amazing results with Machine Learning

Experience

MachineisLearning - Data Science + Machine Learning Help and Advice

Machine Learning Engineer + Data Scientist + Speaker + Teacher + Author

January 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Orange County, California Area

Machine is Learning offers tools and tutorials to help consultants and organizations achieve Machine Learning greatness.

MachineisLearning.com practically guides you through all the techniques, hacks, and algorithms in natural language processing, recommender systems, computer vision, deep learning, and machine learning fields using tools like Tensorflow, PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, Kafka, Spark, Hadoop, SageMaker and many more

Technossus

Data Scientist & Data Architect | Al Solution Lead April 2019 - Present (1 year)

Irvine, California

At Technossus I am responsible for shaping and leading the Artificial Intelligence Practice to ensure high standards and consistent empowerment of both technical and non-technical stakeholders

Responsible for various cloud migrations and architectures specifically for data ingestion on both Azure and AWS

Developed a highly accurate Machine Learning based OCR solution using Morphology, RNN, LSTM and NLP to beat Amazon and Google's solutions, ultimately producing exceptional accuracy

Performed Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Machine Learning prototypes and leading a team of data engineers to deliver a behavior focussed Al solution

Senteon LLC / INV LLC

Principal Architect & Lead Engineer | AI | Data Science | Security June 2018 - March 2019 (10 months)

Greensboro/Winston-Salem, North Carolina Area

- Lead and mentor a team of 10 software and data engineers of various experience levels in implementing a data synchronization solution
- Act as a technical advisor and performed technical due-diligence for various early and later stage startups in an effort to improve architecture, performance and valuation
- Developed a recommender engine with a social media & news feed data scraping solution that utilizes collaborative filtering, LSH, semantic analysis, and content ranking
- Developed a reactive micro-services data framework with an end to end asynchronous event-driven transaction pattern

AvidWare

Principal Data Scientist & Lead ML Engineer | NLP | Computer Vision | Data Science

November 2015 - June 2018 (2 years 8 months)

Greensboro/Winston-Salem, North Carolina Area

AvidWare provides a variety of AI products and custom Machine Learning solutions using the latest data pipeline strategies and machine learning implementations.

- I am leading a team of software engineers while being very hands-on in building natural language processing, recommender systems and computer vision solutions for various problems
- I architect and build data processing pipelines with proven tools such as Kafka, Spark and Hadoop
- I simulate and prototype machine learning models using frameworks such as Keras, Tensorflow, SciKit-Lean, Numpy and Pandas
- I both, test and deploy, production-ready solutions for real-time scalable data solutions in trusted cloud environments such as AWS and Azure
- My responsibilities include collecting, analyzing and normalizing significant amounts of data in an effort to design efficient models that provide accurate decision making and improved analytics
- I provide analytical and statistical analysis to measure quality, improve efficiency and optimization of existing data solutions
- I designed various applications using natural language processing, multiclassification algorithms and clustering techniques to provide the best solution for the problem at hand

Specific technologies:

- Tensorflow, Pytorch, NLTK, Scikit-Learn
- Kafka, Spark, Akka, Play, R, Hadoop, HDFS
- C, C++, Python, Scala, Java

Coronation Fund Managers
Principal Security Architect & Lead Data Engineer
June 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 4 months)
Cape Town Area, South Africa

Software Security Architect and Principal Data Engineer working on an online information system to design a scalable, low latency and highly efficient system.

The system goals were to ensure high security for US\$80 Billion in AUM at the time, while ensuring we meet high performance and stability goals.

The project was delivered in reaching all goals and required minimum ongoing maintenance.

Skills: C/C++, C#, .NET MVC, SQL Server

Nuovetech

Principal Architect & Lead Software Engineer | Security & Cryptography November 2009 - January 2012 (2 years 3 months)

United Kingdom

Working with large organisations like Credit Suisse, GSK, Adams and niche leaders to design, implement and build their scalable, modularized and distributed software systems.

I implemented and built a range of enterprise systems in the financial and telecommunications sector that required the highest standard of performance and security.

I actively developed with .NET MVC, iOS, C++ and OSX platforms to design and deliver a wide range of systems

Specific Skills: C/C++, C#, Objective C, Java, JavaScript, ASP .NET MVC & iOS, Android, Node.js

Education

University of Liverpool

Master of Science (MSc), Software Engineering · (2012 - 2015)

Hillsong International Leadership College

Diploma, Leadership · (2003 - 2005)